(man grunting,
punching bag chains rattling)
(dark, tense music)
(loud grunt)
(machine guns firing)
- Don't move!
(distant muffled shouting)
(sinister music peaks
then fades)
(shrill sinister music builds)
(music fades)
(lighter clicks)
- Not gonna ask how I found ya?
- You can find anyone nowadays.
It's not that impressive.
- Yeah. S'pose that is
fair enough, isn't it?
Look, Knox is alive.
And we found him.
So, we're putting together
a team to go save his ass.
We need a fourth.
More importantly,
I need a point man.
You're the only one I trust.
And you're the only one
that's worked in the unit,
back when Knox was still around.
- Yeah, I remember.
Rest of them are fucking dead
because of you.
- We need
to bring him home, mate.
- Wade and Jace agree to this?
- Of course they do.
We're not gonna
leave a man behind.
- Let me make something
clear to you.
My conscience is clean.
Afghanistan...
that shit was on you
and Anderson,
and no one else.
Knox would agree with me.
He was a good man.
- He is a good man.
That's why we need
to bring him home.
Look, here's an address.
If you decide to join us,
and I hope you do,
meet me there tomorrow morning.
It was good seeing
you again, Marcus.
(tense music)
(siren chirps briefly)
(somber music)
(distant sirens wailing)
(shouting)
(shouting, machine gun firing)
(waves rushing)
(soft tense music)
- So, what now, Briggs?
- We're going to Mexico.
We're going to a town
called Durango.
From there, half a day's walk.
- How we going in?
- It's a covert operation,
snatch and grab.
- Is Anderson in on this?
- She is.
- When do we leave?
- Right now.
(plane roars overhead)
- And I think this is it,
Captain.
- Yeah, this is it.
Anderson, we have confirmation
on the facility. Over.
- Roger that.
Proceed to the facility.
- Wade, Jace,
come forward to this position
and overwatch.
Marcus and I'll move forward
into the facility. Roger that?
(Wade, over radio): Roger that.
We're on the way.
- Roger that. Moving now out.
(soft tense music continues)
(Anderson): Two Tangos
are approaching.
Use your discretion.
(in Spanish)
- I'll take
the one on the right.
You take the one on the left.
- Roger that.
(music builds)
(bullets whiz)
- Clear.
(Briggs): Both targets
neutralized.
(Anderson): Are they cartel?
(Briggs): Affirmative.
(Anderson): Roger that, Captain.
No sign of life
on the outside, Captain.
(Briggs): Roger that, Anderson.
(Anderson): Proceed
with caution.
(Briggs): Wade, move forward
into the facility.
(Wade): Roger that.
Proceeding to the facility.
(Anderson): You've entered
the main level of the facility.
You should have entry points
to the upper and lower floors
from there.
(Briggs): Roger that, Anderson.
Hold left, push right.
Move.
Clear.
Go.
(Anderson): Captain,
do whatever you can
to find his whereabouts.
Gather any information you can.
(Briggs): Affirmative.
(radar beeping)
(Briggs): Room right.
(tense music)
Clear. Moving upstairs.
Clear.
(Anderson): Have you reached
the second story yet,
Captain?
(Briggs): Roger.
Second floor is clear.
- Any sign of Tango 6?
(Briggs): No sign of Tango 6.
Continuing on.
Keep it tight, boys.
Can you smell that?
- Fuck. You seeing this?
- Go or die. It's a warning.
- Is that Knox, Captain?
- No, it isn't.
Knox wouldn't have
gone out like that.
We're gonna find him.
All right. On me, boys.
(low ominous music)
(sharp inhale and exhale)
(ominous music building)
(flesh squelches)
(Anderson): We're reading that
there are multiple
tangos ahead. You're closing in.
(men laughing,
speaking Spanish)
(indistinct chatter continues)
(whistle)
(tense music)
(muffled gag)
- Don't even think about it.
(in Spanish)
(coughs)
- Last chance, compadres.
(Briggs): Marcus,
shut them the fuck up.
- All right, get 'em up.
(gasps)
(bullet whizzes)
(gurgling)
(Briggs): He's bleeding out way
too fucking much. Goddamnit!
Except for these, he's clean.
- Don't wanna waste 'em, right?
- He's got nothing, Briggs.
This doesn't feel right.
Something's off.
- We've got two more levels
to clear
and we need to keep moving.
- Contact.
(Briggs): Anderson,
contact. Over.
- Roger that.
You're free to engage.
(goggles whirring)
- Roger that. Going dark.
(tense music)
(beeping)
- Hey!
(gunshot)
(gunfire)
(grunts)
- Move.
(Briggs): Shotgun. Take cover.
(shotgun blasts)
(automatic gunfire)
Clear.
- Captain.
We spotted multiple tangos
heading into the facility
right now.
You're running out of time.
(Briggs): Affirmative.
- What's the plan, Captain?
This place gives me the creeps.
- What in the hell
is this place?
- Used to be a church.
- Told you.
- Quiet.
(Anderson): Any sign of Tango 6?
- No, but we're not alone.
Get the fuck on the ground!
I will fucking shoot you!
Do you understand?!
(hollow breathing)
- Multiple tangos.
Should we engage?
- Briggs, what is it?
What do you see?
I got a guy
coming up the stairs.
Identify yourself right now!
Put that shit down!
- Grenades, get down!
- Open fire!
(gunfire)
(loud blast)
(high-pitched ringing)
(muffled echoing shouting)
(distorted music)
- Briggs!
I need you to get your ass
on the fucking ground!
(gunshot)
(choking)
(Anderson): Captain Briggs,
can you hear me?
(hollow inhale)
I repeat, can you hear me?
(Briggs): Die! Fucking die!
- Wade? Marcus? Do you copy?
(grunts)
(distorted music continues)
(muffled choking)
(coughing)
(muffled breathing)
(gunshot)
- Anderson, do you copy?
Anderson? Somebody?
(grunts)
- Captain Briggs,
can you hear me?
- They can't hear you.
Our communication's
been cut off.
- Marcus!
- Well then do your job
and get them
back online with me.
We're all they have,
for Christ's sake.
(high-pitched ringing)
(gun blasts)
(coughing)
(monitor beeping)
(sighs)
Fuck this. God.
General, sir, I need to speak
with you. It's urgent.
- Yeah, I'll be with you
in a moment, Agent Anderson.
Isaac, can you pull
this up on radar?
- Yes, sir.
- We lost them.
The whole team went dark.
If I can get an evac team
right now,
they might still have a chance.
- What do you mean
the team went dark?
- Comms went dark.
- Give the agent and I
a moment, would you?
- Yes, sir.
- Walk with me.
(Anderson): We spent months
tracking them down,
scouting out the area,
tracking Knox down.
(General): This isn't the first
time they've engaged
with cartel forces.
- If I can just get
one extraction team,
whichever one that you want.
- Those SEALs were
your extraction team!
They were sent in to get Knox.
How can I justify sending
any more men
over this wild goose chase?
- You know damn well why.
- It's been three years.
Lieutenant Knox has become
nothing more than a Bigfoot.
If that SEAL team is KIA
because of your negligence,
I promise, this ghost hunt
will end now.
I won't authorize any more men
dying over this.
(intense music resonating)
(distorted shouting)
(man): We never stop fighting.
Marcus.
(gasping)
These dogs chasing cars.
(calm music plays briefly)
(birds chirping)
(man): Marcus, you are a wolf.
You're a wolf.
(breathing heavily)
- Is he wounded?
- No. One was wounded.
- No.
- They went out
without a fight,
but we did what we had to do.
- And what will come
of this thing?
- I'm sorry, sir.
I didn't think we...
(muffled gagging)
(man): We never stop fighting.
- Feed him to the dogs.
Put him with the others.
Commodus would like to see
how he does in the arena.
(sinister music peaks
then fades)
- About time.
- So, what is the nature
of this crisis, Sarah?
- I have four of my own MIA,
north of Durango.
We suspect the Sinaloa Cartel
are involved.
- Why hasn't CIA or military
done anything about it?
- It's a long story.
- You know, I can smell shit
on you Americans
like a dog in a pig pen,
and I don't like it.
- Whoever it is,
whatever it is,
we need to make sure
that those SEALs don't suffer
the same fate
as Knox's team did.
(sniffs)
- One hundred thousand each.
- We agreed on 50.
- Now, what is one of your
Americans sayings,
"liquid courage"?
Well, let's just say in Mexico
we have coraje de dinero.
One hundred thousand.
- All right.
But your men better perform.
No half-assing it.
- When have I ever let you down?
(speaking Spanish)
- Die, Americano?
- You wanna end up
like your friend?
The team will win.
- Boy...
there's no need for that.
Just take us to him.
- Marcus, Briggs, come here.
(dark, heavy music)
(men shouting angrily)
- What's going on, Captain?
- Just keep moving
and follow my lead.
- What the fuck is this place?
(man screams in background)
(grunting)
- You piece of shit! Asshole.
(man humming
The Star-Spangled Banner deeply)
(Jace): Marcus! Briggs!
Help me! Wade, help me!
- Come on, man, get off of me.
This is bullshit.
Fuck off me, man.
(grunting)
(camera whirrs)
- Now you can give
the people the eye.
I'm not much
for the fan service,
but... so it's the fans...
- No, no, no! Briggs!
- ...pay much for it.
- Can't fucking see!
- Now, maybe kindness
will be something new.
You just...
(effort grunts)
(man screaming)
(distorted laughter)
- You sick fucks!
What the hell is this?
What have you done to him?!
- Hmm. Perfect timing.
(Jace): Briggs...
- Bring that to me.
(Jace coughing)
(Jace): Help me.
Help me. Help me.
(grunts)
(Jace): Please...
- You hold on, Jace.
We're gonna get you outta here.
You hear me?
We're gonna get you out.
(pained groan)
(grunting)
- Ah, look at that.
(Jace): Ow! Fuck!
- Take him away.
(Jace): Marcus! Wade! Help me!
No. No. Where are you taking me?
Where are you taking me?
(cries in pain)
- Where are they taking him?
- Leave him.
- Is this... is this some
type of live feed?
- If there's anything
you Americans have in common,
it's that you're all
so hypocritical.
You watch pain and violence
on your televisions every day.
You spend millions and millions
of dollars
making it in your Hollywood.
Just how the people like it.
Right?
There isn't a chance you miss
to make violence more...
theatric.
But there is one problem.
None of it is real.
It's disgraceful. Truly.
- So, that's what this is?
You're gonna torture us
for your little snuff films?
- Ah, no. No.
You deserve a bigger role than
to just be
cut to pieces
like your little useless friend.
- Again. Again. Say it again.
I swear I'll rip
your tongue out
and feed it to you, goddamnit.
- You think you can
break my jaw?
Fit your hand down my throat
and rip my tongue out?
Really?
(sardonic laugh)
That would be impressive!
In fact,
I implore you to do this
to one of my men that you fight.
- What are you talking about?
- Surely men of your nature
have heard of the great
gladiators of Rome.
- You're going to make us fight
like gladiators?
(laughs)
What is this?
Is this some kind of joke?
- What about Jace?
Why are you torturing him
and not us?
(breathing heavily)
- There's only so much
you can do with a wounded deer.
Only so much money that can be
made from selling tainted meat.
But if you sell the meat
to the right buyer,
for example,
a farmer who needs something
cheap to feed his dogs,
you'll still get
your money's worth.
Your friend came to us
as a tainted product,
unfortunately because
of our unprofessionalism.
We've already surpassed
15 million Euros.
Your friend has been
a smashing success.
Do not worry, my son.
- Enough!
Take me to him.
- To who, Captain?
- Take me to Knox. Now.
- Hmm. I see.
Unfortunately,
you will not be able to see him
until you've passed
the first ring.
None of you will be able
to see Lieutenant Knox
until you've proven yourselves.
He's spoken of you...
quite often, actually.
He's told me about Afghanistan.
The battles you two fought
together.
The death of your men.
The near-death experience
he experienced
through your...
...carelessness.
You've come all the way here,
just for him.
What do you think will happen
after you come face to face
with him after all this time?
- I guess you'll have
to wait and see, huh?
(laughing)
- Your demeanor is just...
undeniable.
I must admit,
you fit his description to a T.
(sharp exhale)
But now I must ask...
are you ready to fight
for your life one more time?
- Oh, we're ready.
(sardonic laugh)
(clapping)
- Then we shall let
the games begin!
- So, you need to tell me
what's really happening here.
- You're getting paid.
It's a job.
What else do you need to know?
- Devil's in the details.
(bullet whizzes)
- What the fuck was that?
- Sniper on the ridge on my ten.
(cocks gun)
(gunshot blasts)
(grunts)
Give us cover, guys. Follow me.
(tense music)
(gunshots whizzing)
(cocks gun)
(gunshot blasts)
(music fades)
(birds chirping softly)
(sinister music)
(Butcher): Each of you
will be placed
in the fighting draw
individually.
Your opponent is tasked
with one mission,
and one mission only:
to beat you until you are dead.
As a gladiator,
you are to fight in the arena
until you've defeated
your opponent.
Until you have...
slaughtered your opponent.
In honor of the great
games of Rome,
you too will have the honor
of watching your comrades
fight to the death.
(brief laughter)
But...
if any of you
tries to intervene...
you will be shot on sight.
Now, are there any questions,
gentlemen?
(men shouting in background)
- What is this place?
- Your curiosity
is most admirable.
But...
I'd save my breath,
if I were you.
- And who are you?
And all of you?
- We are those
who were once puppets.
Soldiers, as yourselves.
But found our freedom at
the betrayal of our countries.
The titans did not respect
our honor, our lives.
If you survive,
if any of you survive...
you will see.
- Move. Move!
(indistinct chattering)
(clapping)
(grunting)
(loud chatter)
(bones crack)
- Oh!
(echoing laughter)
- Get the fuck off me.
(growling)
- Another exceptional fight
from none other than The Laser!
(cheering and applause)
Up next, we have
a special treat.
For you.
The next opponent has been
a smashing success
in the live chat rooms,
and is going to get
a beating right before
your very eyes.
I present to you,
Jace the Wounded Deer!
(sinister music)
- Is that Jace?
- Jace. Jace?
- It's Jace!
(Briggs): Jace!
(grunts)
Jace, get up! Get up, Jace!
Jace! Get to your feet, soldier!
(Butcher): Who will vouch
for our little wounded deer?
Who will place their bets
on Jace winning this fight?
on the wounded deer
getting his pretty little brains
smashed upon the floor?!
(Briggs): He ain't shit, Jace!
- When you want to play with
the stench of a wounded deer,
there is only one thing
you can do.
Feed it to a bear!
Send him in!
- Oh, shit!
- Yo, we gotta get
in there, y'all.
(growls)
- You're all fucking sick!
- Come on, Jace!
You've got this, Jace!
(cheering, applause)
(Briggs): Jace, you've got this!
Beat that deadbeat to shit!
Fuck this guy.
Fuck you! You're all sick.
- Never tell anyone
what happened here. Promise me.
- You can survive this, Jace.
You can do it.
Just have to fight.
You can do it!
- Hey, hands off him!
- The next bid is set at
a minimum of 800,000 Euros.
You have 60 seconds
to place your bids
before you're booted
from the server.
Thank you
for your participation.
(laughing)
- One million for me.
- You have three new gladiators
in this very room with you now.
Commodus want to profess
that you observe
each and every one of them
during their fight
with their first opponent.
They believe
that because they fight
for the United States,
they can be saved.
Observe within the next
60 seconds,
so that you can make
the most efficient bids
after the fight.
Fighters, prepare for death!
(Briggs): You've got this!
You're a SEAL!
(grunting)
- Begin!
(gunshot cracks)
(shouting)
(grunting)
- Fuck you. Fucking--
Ah!
- Piece of shit!
- You little bitch!
(Jace grunts)
- God.
- Say goodbye to your family!
(thudding blows)
(crowd cheering)
- Get to your feet, Jace!
(rally cry)
Come on, Jace!
- Ah!
- You gotta get up!
- You stand up, Jace.
You stand up, Jace!
(Bear grunting)
(punches thudding)
(crowd clapping)
- God.
(snarls)
- No!
(flesh ripping)
- Ahh!
(spits)
(breathing heavily)
(cheering)
(distorted muffled cheering)
(fire crackling)
(insects chirping)
- Hey, Sarge,
I got a question for you.
- Mm?
(blows)
- What's the craziest thing
you've seen in combat?
- Hmm.
It was Iraq. Second deployment.
We were on a convoy.
We had to supply tanks
front and back escorting.
Tank commander in the front
sitting outside of the turret.
We got ambushed.
(soft tense music)
Rocket came in.
Took his head clean off.
Blood down the side.
I'll never forget that image.
- Sounds like someone zigged
when they should have zagged.
- The fuck you know
about that shit?
- Ladies and gentlemen,
I present to you
Wade and the Cockfighter.
(ominous music)
(scattered cheers)
(grunting)
(depraved laughter)
(onlookers shouting
indistinctly)
(grunting)
(onlookers shouting)
- Ahh! Yah!
(overlapping chatter)
- Oh, my God!
(bones cracking)
- Oh, fuck. Yes!
(music building)
(all exclaiming)
- Fucking right!
- I present to you
Captain Briggs and El Diablo.
- Is that all you've got?!
Is that all you've got?!
- Ah!
(laughing)
(onlookers shouting)
(depraved laughter)
- Yeah? Yeah?
Is this what you want?!
(cheering)
(shouting)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the Boxer versus the Bear.
(onlookers shouting)
(grunting)
(indistinct shouting)
(grunts)
(breathing heavily)
(growls)
(cheering, laughing)
- You're not that big.
You killed my friend.
(grunting)
(breathing loudly)
(Bear): I'm gonna fucking
kill you!
(shouting)
(soft eerie music)
- Ah! Yeah!
(gasping breaths)
(onlookers clap)
- Another exceptional fight
from none other than the Boxer.
Now, the moment
you've all been waiting for...
(panting)
...the kill shot.
(onlookers whoop and clap)
(onlookers jeer)
- You suck! You suck!
- You want him dead so badly,
how 'bout you come over here
and do it yourself?
(woman): Oh, my God!
- You better pick up that
fucking hammer, you pussy.
- You come here
for the rush, don't you?
All of you come here
to feel the power
of taking a man's life,
but you're too afraid
to do it yourselves.
You're cowards. You are sheep!
(panting)
Come on, now pick it up.
Pick it up and do it.
Pick up that hammer. Come on.
- Listen here, asshole,
we paid a lot of money
for you to bash
his fucking head in.
Now go pick up that hammer
and do it, bitch. Fuck you.
- You're coming with me.
(whimpering)
(onlookers shouting)
- Oh, God.
Can someone please help me?
(Marcus): You think
shit is worth it?
Does my pain entertain you?
(whimpering)
'Cause I'm not gonna lie
to you, your
pain would sure as hell
would entertain me.
- Stop!
Somebody do something! Stop!
- What the--
(overlapping concerned chatter)
(muffled cries)
- Let's show your friends
who you really are.
(feed beeps off)
(all shouting)
- That can't be live. No!
- No! No! No!
- Yeah, what the fuck is that?
(muffled, distorted voices)
- Wait, where did you take them?
Answer me!
(panting)
(ominous music swells)
- So much anger.
So much rage.
Reminds me of myself
all those years ago.
You won your first fight.
Your rage should be
liquified now.
You shouldn't waste
your time with anger.
Anger illuminates fear.
What are you afraid of, Marcus?
- Knox.
(tap squeaks on)
(water trickling)
- Do not fear my judgment,
my friend.
I remember the first blood
I spilled
when I was put
into the arena.
(tap turns off)
I finally accepted
that these hands...
they were never meant to kill.
Never meant to destroy.
- You sound like
one of those madmen.
Like that fucking animal
who hosts the fights.
What the hell did
they do to you, Lieutenant?
- I'm no longer a proponent
of any government, Marcus.
I am Commodus.
Neither god nor man.
- You've lost
your mind in this place.
- Until I came here,
I didn't realize
that the orders I followed
for all those years
were the reason
for my own damnation.
- He's fucking mine!
(gunfire)
- All the people that I killed,
maimed,
in the name
of The United States of America
were for nothing.
- Mark my words, Knox,
whatever this place is,
whatever you've done, it's over.
And I'm bringing you home,
even if I have to drag
you through the desert myself!
- You see?
That...
fire inside of you,
that passion,
that is why
you will be my champion.
- What do you mean?
- Only one of you
will survive the arena.
You'll have to prove yourself,
the same way the great Dios
granted me his succession.
Through the purging
of your comrades.
- Wait!
You're forgetting this.
(Knox): You could have
walked away, Marcus.
You had every right.
- Knox!
(screaming)
(man): Sometimes you need
the shadows
to know the worth of the sun.
(soft music)
Kinda like lighthouse, in a way.
(exhales)
Evil men define
that thin red line
between good and bad.
We don't stop fighting.
That's what we do.
Like waves on the rocks,
you just keep crashing
and keep fighting.
(stirring music)
Good men...
Good men are like wolves.
They have foundation.
They're born
from something else.
Resilience, honor.
They stand together.
They fight side by side.
Oh, when they do,
that is a force
to be reckoned with.
(guard): Get up!
(panting)
Did you not hear me?
Get your ass up!
You've got a fight.
(laughs)
Move your ass.
(onlookers cheering)
(fighter grunting)
(snaps)
(muffled cheers and shouts)
(laughing)
- You have been blessed
by the gods.
You're a brute force.
An army of one.
You've earned your rest.
(laughing)
(scattered cheers and applause)
(women groan)
(evil laugh)
- Oh.
(splats)
Marcus.
Marcus, Marcus, Marcus.
You've gained quite a fan base.
But...
I must warn you,
the viewers are upset.
Your fans are... disappointed.
So,
to help you, we've decided
to add to the difficulty.
So, you are to fight
two new fighters.
(sly chuckle)
Don't worry,
we're sportsmanlike.
So, you too shall have help.
An ally, if you would.
A friend, even.
Bring them out.
(chains clanging)
(ominous music)
Two friends, two friends.
Gentlemen, let the fight begin.
(scattered applause)
(grunting, thudding)
(onlookers whooping)
(woman): Do something!
Beat his head in!
(painted grunts, gasps)
(grunting, thudding)
(Briggs): No!
Let me fucking kill him!
Get off me!
Let me kill him! Fuck!
- No. No.
- Fuck!
(Butcher laughs)
- My turn.
Oh, oh!
(grunts)
- Oh!
(Butcher laughing)
(Briggs groaning)
(Knox): Stop.
(music stops abruptly)
(choking)
(coughing)
Escort Briggs back to his cell.
(Briggs coughing)
(gasping)
I haven't given you permission
to die yet, Marcus.
(gasping inhale)
You have one more fight
to prove your worth.
(gate clangs shut)
(dark, stirring music)
(tender music)
(birds chirping)
(man): You are a wolf.
A wolf among sheep.
Remember that.
Marcus.
(guard): Let's go.
Get your ass up!
Commodus wants to see you.
Put this on.
(melodious string music)
(grunts)
- Follow me.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
may I present to you,
our champion,
the one who has given us all
reason to celebrate tonight.
And now,
the one you all traveled
so far to see...
our humble monarch, Commodus.
- My dear friends,
what an exhilarating
evening it has been.
To witness such a magnificent
display of talent and strength
in our champion.
But I'd like
to share with you all
something that's been
on my mind.
(string music continues)
I've brought you here
not just to revel in spectacle
of the arena,
but to show my appreciation
for the extremely
generous contributions
you all have made
to these incredible games.
Without your funding,
we would not have the reach
or power
currently bestowed upon us.
Every one of you represents
progress of our movement,
the evolution of a clear
hierarchy in our species.
I consider each of you
braver than any of the men
who steps foot in the arena.
No offense, Marcus.
- No, it would be my honor
to explore the glory
of the arena
with each and every one of you
at this table.
In fact,
one of you already
had that opportunity. Didn't he?
(gunshot cracks)
- Look at your warrior,
my dear friends.
He speaks with such...
veracity and passion.
This is why he will be
given an opportunity
like only a few men
before him.
Again, I feel it's so important
to thank you all
for your support.
Because of it,
we have grown tenfold
in the last three years.
We are able to reach
men and women of your stature
all around the world now.
In fact, each of you represents
a different country,
creed, or religion.
You see, it's because
of the purity of your blood,
our blood,
that no ocean, mountain,
nor army,
can create a barrier
between us any longer.
Now we have the opportunity
to fully cleanse ourselves
of this world's filth
and bathe in the glory
that the arena brings us.
We have become
what Dios had envisioned.
You see,
Dios believed in a world
without plague,
without famine.
He believed in a world
where the egregious acts
of a few wouldn't exile
the lots of the many.
(coughing)
(frenzied instrumental music)
(all coughing)
(music fades)
You see, Marcus...
In the vast expanse
between light and darkness...
it's the gray
that keeps the balance.
I use my darkness to draw
these people out,
and then eliminate them when
they're brought into the light.
It's a necessary evil.
- So you sacrifice the lives
of the undeserving
so you can get some
self-righteous satisfaction
with killing these rich fucks.
- The people who fight here
are no more innocent
than the people who died
at this table.
Criminals, ex-soldiers,
rapists, murderers...
Many evils extinguished
for the price of one.
Each man at this table
had a chance to be pure.
But they decided to let darkness
overtake them.
Every man here is a bad man.
- Right.
So, Jace was a bad man?
He had a wife and a baby,
for Christ's sakes.
How can you tell me
he deserved death?
- He was a soldier,
just like you and me.
None of us
are innocent here, Marcus.
Wade has taken the lives
of many men and women.
So has Jace.
So have you.
(light ominous music)
(footsteps approach)
(Knox): You know,
when I was first captured
by Dios and his men,
I felt the looming fear
of death consuming me.
The only motivation I had
was to fight for my country.
You see, Marcus,
I know so much
about your mission
because I was sent on the same
exact mission three years ago.
Anderson sent me here
to kill Dios.
Same way she sent
you here to kill me.
- I was never sent here
to kill you.
- Yes. My apologies.
It was Briggs who was
sent here to kill me.
After Dios was neutralized,
I was tasked
to take entire control
over the server,
granting her access to every
penny in the organization.
- It doesn't make any sense.
Anderson could never
get away with that.
- Of course she could.
She got away with Afghanistan.
(rapid gunfire)
(distant screaming)
(Marcus): Four SEALs
killed in the crossfire.
(gunshot cracks)
And Abdul never got taken out
all because of a fuck up.
How do you live with yourself?
How do you sit there and act
like some kind of victim?
- Many would say Dios
was a sick man
for his creation of the arena.
When I first arrived here,
I hated him.
I wanted to kill him,
what he did to my team,
or what he made me
do to my team.
- I'll help you
take down Anderson.
We were brothers once.
And we still are.
Let us help you.
- If you want to take down
Anderson,
there's something
I'm gonna show you first.
(stirring music building)
(music stops abruptly)
(nocturnal animals calling)
- So, who was the sniper?
- What are you talking about?
- No more fucking games, Sarah.
(exhales)
- About a week after Knox
was taken,
we had a contact
in India come across something.
When I got to India,
I was taken to this cyber café.
I was introduced to this hacker.
He came across this online
server that was meant
for some rich fucks
around the world to join in on.
He had taped two
of the livestreams.
The videos depicted
two of my SEALs
fighting other men
to death with their bare hands.
I thought they didn't make it.
Clearly, I was wrong.
It was then I watched Knox
step into the ring.
- What happened to him?
- The fucker won.
He did things
to those men that I never
could imagine a SEAL doing.
(litterfall cracks in distance)
- Yo, what was that?
I'll check it out.
(tense music)
- Whoa!
(gunshots cracking, grunting)
(grunting)
(thudding)
(gun blasts)
- Marcus.
Knox.
- Hello, Captain.
It's been a long time.
- What is this?
Marcus?
What the fuck
is going on here?
- Jace is fucking dead
because of this mission.
You've left another SEAL's
family fatherless
because of your shitty
leadership.
- He's gotten under your skin,
infiltrated your mind.
This isn't you.
You're a soldier.
You fight and die
for the flag.
And so help me God,
the moment you cross that line,
it'll be me
that fucking ends you.
- Anderson doesn't care
about you, Briggs.
Don't you understand that?
Anderson just sent you here
to do what? Kill Knox?
- Knox is a fucking traitor!
And it looks like
you're heading that way too!
- You and Anderson,
you're the monsters
of this place.
This place is just
the pure brutality
of nature itself, but it's fair.
All the things you've done,
all the lies you've told.
- How can he not see
what he did to Jace?!
What he did to all those others
that he slaughtered
in front of the whole
damn world?!
- How does it feel, Captain?
How does it feel
to no longer be in control
of puppets?
- You're dead!
- Wait a minute. Briggs, wait.
- I've been waiting!
Waiting to get my hands on you
so I can squeeze
the fucking life from you!
- Killing him
won't change anything.
Don't you get that?
This thing is worldwide.
- We kill him and it's all over!
- I can't let you kill him.
- If you don't fight with me,
then you fight fucking
against me!
- Think fast.
(groaning)
(thuds)
(Knox groaning)
(Marcus groaning)
(high-pitched ringing)
(muffled groaning)
(laughing)
- Come on, get up.
- You got it.
You got it. You got it.
(indistinct chatter)
- Get up! Come on!
- Come on!
(sounds muffle)
- Fucking pussy.
- Marcus...
Don't you ever stoop down
to their level.
You hear me?
No matter how many
times you fall,
no matter how much it hurts,
you finish it in that ring.
Street fighting,
that's for thugs.
(muffled groans)
(Butcher): All hail, Commodus!
(men): All hail, Commodus!
All hail, Commodus!
(Butcher): All hail, Commodus!
(men): All hail, Commodus!
All hail, Commodus!
(low threatening music)
- I knew nothing
of the artistry of human combat
until I myself became one
with our elder, Dios.
Dios was my master, my teacher.
He showed me the path
to greatness
by unlocking my true potential
in a fight
of uncanny proportions.
(music swells)
It was in this very arena
that I battled
my closest friend,
my brother...
(exhales)
...to his death.
- No.
- Let the fight begin!
(uproarious cheering)
(overlapping shouting)
(grunting)
(grunts)
(shouting continues)
(lands punches, grunting)
- You gotta stop, Briggs.
- You don't get it, do you?
If both of us live,
both of us die.
(grunting)
(loud scream)
(onlookers shouting)
(Briggs): You have to do it,
Marcus.
(heart beating)
- Marcus...
- Die!
- ... you are a wolf.
(blood spurts, groans)
(onlookers shouting)
(gurgling)
- What say you, Commodus?
- I say, what's a trophy
without a head?
(onlookers exclaiming)
(all shouting)
- Ah. Finish him.
(onlookers shouting)
- Are you ready, my son?
- Yes.
(thuds)
(rally cry)
(machine guns firing)
(sinister music)
(shouting)
(Marcus grunts)
(gunshots crack)
(machine gunfire)
(tense music)
(gunshots crack)
(machine gun fires rapidly)
(sweeping ominous music)
(gunshots crack)
(gun clicking)
(grunting, punching)
(breathing heavily)
(grunting)
(machine gun fires rapidly)
(Butcher): Your fate,
dear Brutus,
lies not in the stars...
(groaning)
..but within ourselves.
(knife swishes)
(groans)
(blood spurting, gasping)
(breathing heavily)
(spits)
(tense music)
(Wade): Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
(men shouting)
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
What the hell
are you doing here?
- Where's Knox?
- Are you the extraction team?
Where's the rest of 'em?
- We're all that's left.
- Shit.
- Where's Knox, Wade?
- Marcus went after him.
And Knox, he's gone mad.
- What about Briggs?
- Jace and Briggs,
they didn't make it.
- I'm sorry it had
to go this way, Wade.
(gunshots firing)
(Wade): Anderson...
(gunshot cracks)
- We need to find
Marcus and Knox.
(Knox): We aren't good men,
Marcus.
None of us.
This is where we belong.
- It's over, Knox.
Get up. We're leaving.
- I'm not going anywhere,
Marcus.
You have to kill me.
(Anderson): What happened,
Briggs?
(coughing)
I gave you a second chance
and you fucked it up all again.
(coughing)
- Fuck you, cunt.
(spits)
(coughing)
- I'm not saving
you again, Briggs.
(gunshot cracks)
- She sent me here
to pay her back
for the cover up.
At the time I felt like
I didn't have a choice.
- And you took over.
You took her chance
of profiting from this place.
From controlling it.
- The stream itself
was worth billions.
Anderson knew
she could run it
from the shadows.
- So, she sent Briggs
to clean up her mess.
- Precisely.
(footsteps approach)
- Marcus... put it down, Marcus.
(Marcus): You gonna
shoot me, Anderson?
- You killed Briggs.
You're a traitor.
- I had no choice.
You know that.
You know exactly what's
going on here, don't you?
- Do you wanna be a hero,
or do you wanna be
a terrorist like him?
- He's not a terrorist.
He's a SEAL.
Now I believe that he needs
to be held accountable
for the horrors of this place,
but he's no monster.
He's a product
of this environment.
We came here to rescue him
from this madness,
and we trusted you to help us!
(Anderson): It's bigger
than you think, Marcus.
You're not even scratching
the surface.
- I know it is,
and he's the key.
We need him.
- You're right, I do need him.
Knox,
did you really think
you could hide away
from me forever?
That I wouldn't come
catch up with you?
- I knew one day you'd send
your hounds after me.
I didn't think
I'd be lucky enough
to see you in person, though.
- You're gonna take me
to the server room,
and you're gonna give me
those passwords.
- Server room?
I don't even know where it is.
- I'm not asking you again!
- You know why you're no longer
a step ahead of me, Anderson?
Because fear is what
was holding me back.
The man you knew is dead
and the entity before you
is incapable of fear.
It doesn't fear humiliation,
failure, or death, like you do.
You can kill a man,
even a god,
but you can't kill an idea.
Isn't that right, Marcus?
But this is how
I kill you, Anderson.
(gunshot cracks)
- Knox! Knox!
(sounds muffle)
(Knox): You're protectors
of gods.
(Anderson panting)
- It's over, Anderson.
- You little fuck.
(grunting)
(blood spurting)
(grunts)
(lands punches)
(Marcus groans)
(coughing, gasping)
(panicked groaning)
- This is for Knox.
(blood spurts)
(choking, gasping)
Are you a wolf?
- Yes.
- Then we have work to do.
(ominous music peaks
and fades quickly)
(Marcus): I sometimes dream
that I'm in a tunnel.
(soft music)
The way behind me is crumbling.
And so, I have no choice but
to move forward into the light.
But I don't know
what's waiting for me there.
(insects chirping)
(phone buzzing)
(call beeps on)
- Yes. I have everything
prepared for what's to come.
It's truly an honor.
I won't let you down.
(grunting)
(breathing heavily)
(tense music)
I'm a United States General.
You must have a death wish.
(grunts)
- How ironic.
(mocking laugh)
- You don't know the half
of who you're dealing with.
They'll never let you live.
- Well, that's fine,
'cause we're already dead.
(sweeping instrumental music)
(Marcus): My father showed me
how to be a man.
But after all
the monsters I've seen,
I can only be the wolf.
(ominous music)